

Tbilisi, Georgia

 \square (+995) 591-029-428 | \square zhukovsd@gmail.com | \square zhukovsd | \square zhukovsd

Summary.

Software architect with 13 years of professional development experience. My position in the projects is usually a combination of architect, team lead and fullstack developer roles. I mainly focus on Java/Kotlin stack and DevOps/cloud technologies, but also have professional experience in Frontend and Desktop development. My passion is to start projects from the drawing board and deliver production ready solutions.

Skills _

Cloud services AWS (EKS, DynamoDB, Keyspaces, CDK, CloudFormation and more), DigitalOcean (DO Kubernetes)

DevOps Kubernetes, Docker, Bash, CI/CD (Jenkins, CircleCI), IaC (AWS CDK), Prometheus

Backend development Java (Core, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Spring Data, Spring Security and more), Kotlin

Web development Javascript 2015 (ES6), Typescript, Webpack, SCSS/LESS

Databases SQL DBs (MySQL, Postgres, AuroraDB), NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis), Distributed DBs (DynamoDB, Cassandra)

Education

ITMO State University

Saint Petersburg, Russia

B.S. IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND TECHNOLOGIES

2007 - 2012

Experience _____

Code Partners Remote

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT / FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

June 2017 - present

- · Joined the company as a Senior Developer to work on various outsourcing projects. Later switched to Architect/Lead position to develop startup projects initiated within the company
- · As an architect, I'm involved in designing project requirements, responsible for solution architecture, setting up and managing cloud infrastructure and CI/CD pipelines
- As a lead, I interview and onboard team members, delegate tasks and review the results
- · As a developer, I design and implement various parts of the system backend, storage layer, cloud infrastructure, CI/CD, frontend

Upwork Remote

• My Upwork profile (currently private)

- Average project rating 5.00/5.00
- 20 projects in different areas:
 - Java

FREELANCER

- · Javascript/jQuery
- Windows and MacOS installers
- · Various desktop projects: launcher and installer for a MMO game, custom Chromium build, visual components for Delphi VCL

VBrand Remote

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Mar. 2017 - May 2017

2016 - 2017

- Implemented a screen capturing system (PowerShell, FFmpeg)
- Designed and developed a client-server application for video processing (cutting/merging/converting). RESTful API; Backend Java, FFmpeg; Frontend - Javascript, Bootstrap, ¡Query

SERGEY ZHUKOV · CV FEBRUARY 1, 2023

ITVA Saint Petersburg, Russia

 DESKTOP DEVELOPER
 2010 - 2017

- Lead developer on a number of projects:
 - Native Windows applications
 - Cross-platform applications for Windows and MacOS
 - Web services
 - · Libraries for internal usage within a team (internationalization library, persistent settings library)
- Was responsible for development and release of more than 10 software products
- · Used technologies:
 - Programming languages: Delphi, C++, Javascript
 - UI frameworks: VCL, Firemonkey, Skinbuilder, Sciter, CEF
 - · Libraries and databases: libtorrent, bass, MySQL, FireDAC, SQLite

Notable work projects _

Cloud logging solution

KOTLIN, SPRING BOOT, KUBERNETES, DYNAMODB

2021 - current

- Cloud logging tool, allowing developers to collect logs from the instances of their applications, which may be backend or desktop apps, and then inspect them
- The project is currently in the the pre-launch phase, I work on formalizing functional requirements, choosing technologies, designing the architecture, delegating tasks to the team, implementing the core functionality

DevOps marketplace

JAVA, SPRING BOOT, PHP, KUBERNETES, DOCKER, JENKINS

2019 - 2021

- DevOps marketplace, allowing developers to sell their products and support to the customers. A key feature of the project is programmatic integration with DevOps platforms, such as Jenkins
- My role:
 - Design functional requirements, UI mockups
 - · Develop parts of the system backend services, web application, integrations with external services
 - Delegate tasks to designers and developers
 - Manage project infrastructure cloud environments (Kubernetes) and CI/CD pipelines (Jenkins)

An application for processing video content

JAVA, JAVASCRIPT, BOOTSTRAP

2017

- A client-server application for processing (cutting/merging/converting) video content. Typical usage is to create highlights clip from a show or
 to cut out ads from a broadcast record
- Architecture:
 - Backend Java, FFmpeg
 - Frontend Javascript, Bootstrap, ¡Query
- Backend service exposes RESTful API which serves requests from web app UI views

LoviOtvet

DELPHI 2010 - 2012

- Smart calculator for solving and simplifying math expressions and equations
- Self-implemented solving engine based on reverse polish notation builds a simplifications tree which allows displaying a solution in step-bystep fashion
- · Supported math operations:
 - Common and decimal fraction operations
 - Polynomial operations including division
 - Solving linear and square equations
- · A web service based on solving engine exposes RESTful API and serves requests from mobile clients and web application
- Freeware desktop, mobile and web clients were released for CIS market. Mobile clients have 500k+ installs, the backend app served more than 12 millions of requests

Self-motivated projects _____

Mentoring, course writing, blogging

<u>Practical Java cours</u>

2017 - current

- As a non-commercial side project, I mentor developers (mainly Java, but also Python, PHP), helping them to build their skills and get a job
- · I've created a practical Java course (in Russian), consisting of 7 pet project, covering all the major Java Backend topics
- My one-on-one mentoring to the students includes: creating a learning plan, code review, advice on how to improve their skills, and helping
 them to write a CV and prepare for interviews
- 4 of my students have already got a job, and 2 more are in the process of interviewing
- I blog about mentoring on Telegram, and stream live coding sessions and some of the project reviews on YouTube